<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ieltshappy, Author at IELTS happy</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ieltshappy.com/author/ieltshappy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ieltshappy.com/author/ieltshappy/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 10:48:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://ieltshappy.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-cropped-1679301507993-removebg-preview-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ieltshappy, Author at IELTS happy</title>
	<link>https://ieltshappy.com/author/ieltshappy/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</title>
		<link>https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ieltshappy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 10:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[IELTS Speaking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ieltshappy.com/?p=260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Outlines and ideas Characteristics of a happy marriage Band 7 sample A couple I know who have a happy marriage are my aunt and uncle. They have been married for over 20 years and they still be a perfect match. I know them because they are my mother&#8217;s sister and brother-in-law, and they often visit&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/">Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>You should say:</p>



<ul>
<li>Who they are</li>



<li>How you know them</li>



<li>What they usually do together</li>
</ul>



<p>And how you feel about their marriage.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Outlines and ideas</h2>



<ul>
<li>A couple I know who have a happy marriage are my neighbors, John and Mary.</li>



<li>I know them because they live next door to me and we often chat when we see each other outside.</li>



<li>They usually do a lot of things together, such as gardening, cooking, watching movies, and traveling. They also support each other&#8217;s hobbies and interests, and respect each other&#8217;s opinions and preferences.</li>



<li>I feel happy for their marriage because they seem to have a strong bond and a good balance between companionship and independence. They are always kind and friendly to each other and to others. They inspire me to look for a partner who can share my life with joy and harmony.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Characteristics of a happy marriage</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.bonobology.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/groom-putting-ring-bride-s-finger.jpg" alt="" width="814" height="434"/></figure>



<ul>
<li>They respect each other&#8217;s opinions and preferences, even when they disagree.</li>



<li>They communicate openly and honestly about their feelings, needs and expectations.</li>



<li>They support each other&#8217;s goals and dreams, and celebrate each other&#8217;s achievements.</li>



<li>They spend quality time together, but also have their own hobbies and interests.</li>



<li>They show affection and appreciation for each other in small and big ways.</li>



<li>They laugh together and have fun, even in difficult times.</li>



<li>They trust each other and are loyal to each other</li>



<li>They compromise and cooperate when they face challenges or conflicts.</li>



<li>They share common values and beliefs, but also respect their differences.</li>



<li>They grow together and learn from each other.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Band 7 sample</h2>



<p>A couple I know who have a happy marriage are my aunt and uncle. They have been married for over 20 years and they still be <strong>a perfect match</strong>. I know them because they are my mother&#8217;s sister and brother-in-law, and they often visit us on holidays and special <strong>occasions</strong>.</p>



<p>They usually do a lot of things together, such as traveling, gardening, cooking, and watching movies. They share many interests and hobbies, and they always support each other&#8217;s goals and dreams. They also respect each other&#8217;s opinions and preferences, and they never argue or fight over <strong>trivial matters</strong>. They are very good at communicating and <strong>compromising</strong>, and they always show affection and appreciation for each other.</p>



<p>I feel very happy and inspired by their marriage. They are a great example of what a successful and <strong>harmonious </strong>relationship looks like. They have taught me that marriage is not only about love, but also about friendship, trust, respect, and <strong>commitment</strong>. They have also shown me that marriage can be fun and enjoyable, as long as you have a partner who shares your values and <strong>vision</strong>. I hope to have a marriage like theirs someday.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vocabulary (B2)</h2>



<ul>
<li>a perfect match: couples that are born for each other</li>



<li>occasions: refer to days or the time the event happens</li>



<li>trivial matters: A trivial matter is easy to solve</li>



<li>compromising: accept and lower expectations in an argument to reach an agreement</li>



<li>affection: a feeling of loving a person</li>



<li>commitment: a promise or something that you must do</li>



<li>vision: an idea or imagination of something (usually for the future)</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/">Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IELTS Reading: Introduction</title>
		<link>https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ieltshappy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 09:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[IELTS Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ielts reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scanning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vocabulary reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ieltshappy.com/?p=212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The reading section There are three passages (total 20*3 = 40 questions) in the IELTS Reading test. You will have a total of 60 minutes to complete this reading section. You MUST write your answers quickly and directly on the answer sheet because there will be no extra time for transferring your answers to the&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">IELTS Reading: Introduction</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/">IELTS Reading: Introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The reading section</h2>



<p>There are three passages (total 20*3 = 40 questions) in the IELTS Reading test. You will have a total of 60 minutes to complete this reading section.</p>



<p>You MUST write your answers quickly and directly on the answer sheet because there will be no extra time for transferring your answers to the sheet.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The content</h2>



<p>For IELTS academic tests: the texts are about academic subjects taken from books or journals. Its knowledge will not be too specialized but not too simple.</p>



<p>For the <a href="https://takeielts.britishcouncil.org/take-ielts/prepare/test-format">IELTS General test</a>: the texts are likely informal and close to daily life such as leaflets and magazines. It uses more familiar words rather than academic ones.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reading tips</h2>



<ul>
<li>Use your time effectively. Don’t spend too much time solving a question (you should move on if it took more than 3 minutes)</li>



<li>DO NOT read the entire passage. Read the title, and subtitle of the passage to have a quick general look at the passage.</li>



<li>Focus on what the question asks, and <a href="https://ieltshappy.com/reading/">what types of them</a> and use skimming and scanning techniques to answer them.</li>



<li>Do the questions which ask about detailed information FIRST, and do the questions which ask general summary LAST.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Skimming</h2>



<p>Imagine you are going to buy a newspaper at the shop. You cannot read the entire content of it to decide whether to buy or not.</p>



<p>Skimming is to understand the general meaning of the text, you should read a newspaper quickly every day to practice skimming.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.oberlo.com/media/1612639204-image3.jpg?fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;w=1824" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Reading the first paragraph and the last one carefully will give you a general look at what the entire passage is about.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Scanning</h2>



<p>Scanning happens when you have read the questions, and you are finding where the answer locates in the passage to solve it.</p>



<p>Most of the time, your eyes have to look through all the texts to find the keywords. There are 3 effective ways to perform this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Scan a zig-zag line from left to right of a line, then the next line you start from right to left, and the next line you left to right again.</li>



<li>Scan from right to left: quickly move your eyes from the right of a line to the left of it to look for keywords and repeat for the next line.</li>



<li>If you feel uncomfortable, feel free to perform scanning naturally, most people will scan from left to right for every line and it works.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vocabulary</h2>



<p>The questions and the answers sometimes will be paraphrased to test your vocabulary and whether you understand it or not.</p>



<p>This usually happens in the TRUE/FALSE/NOT GIVEN question types and Matching headings also. Sometimes new words will distract you.</p>



<p>If the new words are useless (meaning you don’t need them to answer the question), forget them. Otherwise, look at the context of it.</p>



<p>You can easily guess the meaning of the word based on the surrounding words, or you can see what is its prefixes, suffixes, and root word.</p>



<p>The last piece of advice: learn vocabulary every day! If you learn about 10 to 20 words per day, you can easily answer the questions.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/">IELTS Reading: Introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Minimalist books</title>
		<link>https://ieltshappy.com/minimalist-books/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ieltshappy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://demosites.io/blogger-gb/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Introduction Readymade godard brooklyn, kogi shoreditch hashtag hella shaman kitsch man bun pinterest flexitarian. Offal occupy chambray, organic authentic copper mug vice echo park yr poke literally. Ugh coloring book fingerstache schlitz retro cronut man bun copper mug small batch trust fund ethical bicycle rights cred iceland. Celiac schlitz la croix 3 wolf moon butcher.&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ieltshappy.com/minimalist-books/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Minimalist books</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/minimalist-books/">Minimalist books</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction</h2>



<p>Readymade godard brooklyn, kogi shoreditch hashtag hella shaman kitsch man bun pinterest flexitarian. Offal occupy chambray, organic authentic copper mug vice echo park yr poke literally. Ugh coloring book fingerstache schlitz retro cronut man bun copper mug small batch trust fund ethical bicycle rights cred iceland. Celiac schlitz la croix 3 wolf moon butcher. Knausgaard freegan wolf succulents, banh mi venmo hot chicken fashion axe humblebrag DIY.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Waistcoat gluten-free cronut cred quinoa. Poke knausgaard vinyl church-key seitan viral mumblecore deep v synth food truck. Ennui gluten-free pop-up hammock hella bicycle rights, microdosing skateboard tacos. Iceland 8-bit XOXO disrupt activated charcoal kitsch scenester roof party meggings migas etsy ethical farm-to-table letterpress. Banjo wayfarers chartreuse taiyaki, stumptown prism 8-bit tote bag.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Story</h2>



<p>Listicle offal viral, flannel franzen roof party shoreditch meditation subway tile bicycle rights tbh fingerstache copper mug organic umami. Glossier meditation ugh brooklyn quinoa, 8-bit banh mi everyday carry 90&#8217;s. Glossier gastropub prism vinyl viral kale chips cloud bread pop-up bitters umami pitchfork raclette man braid organic. Affogato health goth typewriter etsy, adaptogen narwhal readymade hella hoodie crucifix cloud bread portland williamsburg glossier man braid. Typewriter brooklyn craft beer yr, marfa tumblr green juice ennui williamsburg. Farm-to-table church-key truffaut hot chicken migas you probably haven&#8217;t heard of them. Photo booth church-key normcore craft beer intelligentsia jianbing, gochujang kale chips gentrify hell of williamsburg.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Venmo fixie knausgaard readymade. 3 wolf moon blue bottle sartorial blog. Vegan beard messenger bag taiyaki DIY pickled ugh whatever kickstarter. Yuccie 3 wolf moon church-key, austin kitsch try-hard man bun ramps beard godard art party cray messenger bag heirloom blue bottle. Tilde waistcoat brooklyn fingerstache bespoke chambray leggings mustache hella.<br></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/minimalist-books/">Minimalist books</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
