<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ielts reading Archives - IELTS happy</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ieltshappy.com/tag/ielts-reading/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ieltshappy.com/tag/ielts-reading/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 17:02:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://ieltshappy.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-cropped-1679301507993-removebg-preview-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ielts reading Archives - IELTS happy</title>
	<link>https://ieltshappy.com/tag/ielts-reading/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>IELTS Reading: Introduction</title>
		<link>https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ieltshappy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 09:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[IELTS Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ielts reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scanning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vocabulary reading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ieltshappy.com/?p=212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The reading section There are three passages (total 20*3 = 40 questions) in the IELTS Reading test. You will have a total of 60 minutes to complete this reading section. You MUST write your answers quickly and directly on the answer sheet because there will be no extra time for transferring your answers to the&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">IELTS Reading: Introduction</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/">IELTS Reading: Introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The reading section</h2>



<p>There are three passages (total 20*3 = 40 questions) in the IELTS Reading test. You will have a total of 60 minutes to complete this reading section.</p>



<p>You MUST write your answers quickly and directly on the answer sheet because there will be no extra time for transferring your answers to the sheet.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The content</h2>



<p>For IELTS academic tests: the texts are about academic subjects taken from books or journals. Its knowledge will not be too specialized but not too simple.</p>



<p>For the <a href="https://takeielts.britishcouncil.org/take-ielts/prepare/test-format">IELTS General test</a>: the texts are likely informal and close to daily life such as leaflets and magazines. It uses more familiar words rather than academic ones.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reading tips</h2>



<ul>
<li>Use your time effectively. Don’t spend too much time solving a question (you should move on if it took more than 3 minutes)</li>



<li>DO NOT read the entire passage. Read the title, and subtitle of the passage to have a quick general look at the passage.</li>



<li>Focus on what the question asks, and <a href="https://ieltshappy.com/reading/">what types of them</a> and use skimming and scanning techniques to answer them.</li>



<li>Do the questions which ask about detailed information FIRST, and do the questions which ask general summary LAST.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Skimming</h2>



<p>Imagine you are going to buy a newspaper at the shop. You cannot read the entire content of it to decide whether to buy or not.</p>



<p>Skimming is to understand the general meaning of the text, you should read a newspaper quickly every day to practice skimming.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.oberlo.com/media/1612639204-image3.jpg?fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;w=1824" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Reading the first paragraph and the last one carefully will give you a general look at what the entire passage is about.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Scanning</h2>



<p>Scanning happens when you have read the questions, and you are finding where the answer locates in the passage to solve it.</p>



<p>Most of the time, your eyes have to look through all the texts to find the keywords. There are 3 effective ways to perform this:</p>



<ul>
<li>Scan a zig-zag line from left to right of a line, then the next line you start from right to left, and the next line you left to right again.</li>



<li>Scan from right to left: quickly move your eyes from the right of a line to the left of it to look for keywords and repeat for the next line.</li>



<li>If you feel uncomfortable, feel free to perform scanning naturally, most people will scan from left to right for every line and it works.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vocabulary</h2>



<p>The questions and the answers sometimes will be paraphrased to test your vocabulary and whether you understand it or not.</p>



<p>This usually happens in the TRUE/FALSE/NOT GIVEN question types and Matching headings also. Sometimes new words will distract you.</p>



<p>If the new words are useless (meaning you don’t need them to answer the question), forget them. Otherwise, look at the context of it.</p>



<p>You can easily guess the meaning of the word based on the surrounding words, or you can see what is its prefixes, suffixes, and root word.</p>



<p>The last piece of advice: learn vocabulary every day! If you learn about 10 to 20 words per day, you can easily answer the questions.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/ielts-reading-introduction/">IELTS Reading: Introduction</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
