<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>IELTS Speaking Archives - IELTS happy</title>
	<atom:link href="https://ieltshappy.com/category/ielts-speaking/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://ieltshappy.com/category/ielts-speaking/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 10:45:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://ieltshappy.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-cropped-1679301507993-removebg-preview-32x32.png</url>
	<title>IELTS Speaking Archives - IELTS happy</title>
	<link>https://ieltshappy.com/category/ielts-speaking/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</title>
		<link>https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ieltshappy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 10:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[IELTS Speaking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ieltshappy.com/?p=260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Outlines and ideas Characteristics of a happy marriage Band 7 sample A couple I know who have a happy marriage are my aunt and uncle. They have been married for over 20 years and they still be a perfect match. I know them because they are my mother&#8217;s sister and brother-in-law, and they often visit&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/">Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>You should say:</p>



<ul>
<li>Who they are</li>



<li>How you know them</li>



<li>What they usually do together</li>
</ul>



<p>And how you feel about their marriage.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Outlines and ideas</h2>



<ul>
<li>A couple I know who have a happy marriage are my neighbors, John and Mary.</li>



<li>I know them because they live next door to me and we often chat when we see each other outside.</li>



<li>They usually do a lot of things together, such as gardening, cooking, watching movies, and traveling. They also support each other&#8217;s hobbies and interests, and respect each other&#8217;s opinions and preferences.</li>



<li>I feel happy for their marriage because they seem to have a strong bond and a good balance between companionship and independence. They are always kind and friendly to each other and to others. They inspire me to look for a partner who can share my life with joy and harmony.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Characteristics of a happy marriage</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.bonobology.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/groom-putting-ring-bride-s-finger.jpg" alt="" width="814" height="434"/></figure>



<ul>
<li>They respect each other&#8217;s opinions and preferences, even when they disagree.</li>



<li>They communicate openly and honestly about their feelings, needs and expectations.</li>



<li>They support each other&#8217;s goals and dreams, and celebrate each other&#8217;s achievements.</li>



<li>They spend quality time together, but also have their own hobbies and interests.</li>



<li>They show affection and appreciation for each other in small and big ways.</li>



<li>They laugh together and have fun, even in difficult times.</li>



<li>They trust each other and are loyal to each other</li>



<li>They compromise and cooperate when they face challenges or conflicts.</li>



<li>They share common values and beliefs, but also respect their differences.</li>



<li>They grow together and learn from each other.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Band 7 sample</h2>



<p>A couple I know who have a happy marriage are my aunt and uncle. They have been married for over 20 years and they still be <strong>a perfect match</strong>. I know them because they are my mother&#8217;s sister and brother-in-law, and they often visit us on holidays and special <strong>occasions</strong>.</p>



<p>They usually do a lot of things together, such as traveling, gardening, cooking, and watching movies. They share many interests and hobbies, and they always support each other&#8217;s goals and dreams. They also respect each other&#8217;s opinions and preferences, and they never argue or fight over <strong>trivial matters</strong>. They are very good at communicating and <strong>compromising</strong>, and they always show affection and appreciation for each other.</p>



<p>I feel very happy and inspired by their marriage. They are a great example of what a successful and <strong>harmonious </strong>relationship looks like. They have taught me that marriage is not only about love, but also about friendship, trust, respect, and <strong>commitment</strong>. They have also shown me that marriage can be fun and enjoyable, as long as you have a partner who shares your values and <strong>vision</strong>. I hope to have a marriage like theirs someday.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vocabulary (B2)</h2>



<ul>
<li>a perfect match: couples that are born for each other</li>



<li>occasions: refer to days or the time the event happens</li>



<li>trivial matters: A trivial matter is easy to solve</li>



<li>compromising: accept and lower expectations in an argument to reach an agreement</li>



<li>affection: a feeling of loving a person</li>



<li>commitment: a promise or something that you must do</li>



<li>vision: an idea or imagination of something (usually for the future)</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/describe-a-couple-you-know-who-have-a-happy-marriage/">Describe a couple you know who have a happy marriage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://ieltshappy.com/">IELTS happy</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
